Guide to the Walter Stainton papers, 1914-1983
Stainton, Walter papers, 1914-1983
- Series VII. Cornell Dramatic Club
  - Administration Documents
    - Cornell Dramatic Club Information Sheets and Note Cards About Summer Theatre, 1948, 1948 (Box 7, Folder 53)
    - Cornell Dramatic Club Performance Announcement and Note About Casting, 1950, 1950 (Box 7, Folder 55)
    - Misc. Lists of Dramatic Club Councils (Box 7, Folder 56)
    - Cornell Student Activities Papers (Box 8, Folder 54)
    - Cornell Dramatic Club Papers, Contains protocol for audiences and training notes. (Box 8, Folder 64)
    - Assorted Cornell Dramatic Club Papers (Box 8, Folder 65)
    - Report of the Stage Manager for the Year 1919-1920, 1920, June 2, 1920 (Box 8, Folder 107)
    - Cornell Dramatic Club Constitutions, 1920/June 1948 (Box 8, Folder 110)
    - Notes for Theatre Staff Meeting and Minutes for Cornell Dramatic Club Meeting, September 18, 1951/May 10, 1948 (Box 8, Folder 111)
    - Cornell Dramatic Club By-Laws, June 1948, June 1948 (Box 8, Folder 112)
    - Amendments to Cornell Dramatic Club Constitution, 1948, 1948 (Box 8, Folder 113)
    - Financial Report of the Cornell Dramatic Club for the Season 1952-1953, 1952-1953 (Box 8, Folder 115)
    - Summary of Cornell Dramatic Club Members, April 1953, April 27, 1953 (Box 8, Folder 116)
  - Financial Documents
    - Check to M. M. Gutstadt from Cornell Dramatic Club, November 23, 1992, November 23, 1922 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Cornell Dramatic Club: Report of Financial Operations: 1941-1943, September 1, 1941-September 1, 1943 (Box 7, Folder 50)
    - Cornell Dramatic Club Financial and Technical Notes (Box 8, Folder 117)
  - Correspondence
    - Notes and Correspondence About Cornell Dramatic Club Students Visiting Skidmore College, October 1938, October 1938 (Box 8, Folder 69)
    - Correspondence Concerning Collaboration Between Cornell Dramatic Club and Wells College, October-November 1939, October-November 1939 (Box 8, Folder 70)
    - Assorted Correspondence Concerning Cornell Dramatic Club, 1940-1948, 1940-1948 (Box 8, Folder 71)
    - Correspondence Concerning Cornell Dramatic Club's Presentation of "Pyramus and Thisbe," August-October 1951, August-October 1951 (Box 8, Folder 72)
    - Assorted Correspondence Concerning Cornell Dramatic Club, 1952-1953, 1952-1953 (Box 8, Folder 73)
    - Papers and Correspondence Concerning Cornell Dramatic Club's First President's Prize, May-June 1959, May-June 1959 (Box 8, Folder 74)
    - Correspondence Between Smiley Blanton and Burton Spiller About Formation of Cornell Dramatic Club, April 1952, April 1952; Also postcard to Spiller from Jack Donaldson, June 1952. (Box 8, Folder 75)
    - The Cornell Dramatic Club Annual Letter to Former Members, 1924-1967, 1924-1967 (Box 8, Folder 98)
    - The Cornell Dramatic Club Newsletter, 1924-1967, 1924-1967 (Box 8, Folder 99)
    - Cornell Dramatic Club Annual Letter to Former Members, 1945-1949, 1945-1949 (Box 8, Folder 100)
    - Cornell Dramatic Club Newsletter, October 25, 1948, October 25, 1948 (Box 8, Folder 101)
    - Cornell Dramatic Club Newsletter, 1951-1952, 1951-1952 (Box 8, Folder 102)
    - "Annual Letter Cornell Dramatic Club Season 1956-1957", 1956-1957 (Box 8, Folder 103)
    - Cornell Dramatic Club Biennial Letter, 1963-1965, 1963-1965 (Box 8, Folder 104)
    - Cornell Dramatic Club Annual Letter to Former Members (Box 8, Folder 105)
    - Correspondence and Paperwork Concerning Cornell Dramatic Club's Performance of The Winslow Boy in Buffalo, NY, 1949, 1949 (Box 8, Folder 114)
    - Correspondence Concerning Mount Union College's Theatre, February-March 1951, February-March 1951 (Box 12, Folder 37)
    - Correspondence Concerning Cornell Performing Arts Center, 1979-1983, 1979-1983 (Box 12, Folder 39)
    - Financial and Administrative Documents Concerning Cornell Dramatic Club and Willard Straight Hall, 1954-1955, 1954-1955 (Box 12, Folder 50)
    - Financial and Administrative Documents Concerning Cornell Dramatic Club and Willard Straight Hall, 1954-1957, 1954-1957 (Box 12, Folder 51)
    - Financial and Administrative Documents Concerning Cornell Dramatic Club and Willard Straight Hall, 1955-1957, 1955-1957 (Box 12, Folder 52)
    - Financial and Administrative Documents Concerning Cornell Dramatic Club, 1957-1959, 1957-1959 (Box 12, Folder 53)
    - Financial and Administrative Documents Concerning Cornell Dramatic Club and Willard Straight Hall, 1960s, 1960s (Box 12, Folder 54)
  - CDC 50th Anniversary
    - Remarks by Former Cornell Dramatic Club Presidents Concerning 50th Anniversary, 1958, 1958 (Box 8, Folder 76)
    - Correspondence and Documents Concerning Cornell Dramatic Club's 50th Anniversary, 1958=1959, 1958-1959 (Box 8, Folder 77)
    - Ithaca Journal Issue with Article About Cornell Dramatic Club's 50th Anniversary, March 7, 1959, March 7, 1959 (Box 8, Folder 79)
    - Letters R.S.V.P.-ing to Cornell Dramatic Club 50th Anniversary Dinner, April-June 1959, April-June 1959 (Box 8, Folder 80)
    - Letters Declining Attendance at Cornell Dramatic Club 50th Anniversary Dinner, May-June 1959, May-June 1959 (Box 8, Folder 81)
    - Thank You Letters to Those Who Attended the Cornell Dramatic Club 50th Anniversary Dinner, June-August 1959, June-August 1959 (Box 8, Folder 82)
    - Assorted Notes Concerning Cornell Dramatic Club 50th Anniversary, 1959 (Box 8, Folder 83)
    - The Cornell Dramatic Club Fiftieth-Anniversary Letter, 1949, 1959 (Box 8, Folder 84)
    - Programs from Cornell Dramatic Club's Fiftieth Anniversary Season, 1959, 1959 (Box 8, Folder 85)
    - Cornell Dramatic Club's 50th Anniversary Luncheon (Box 8, Folder 86)
    - Assorted Correspondence Concerning Cornell Dramatic Club 50th Anniversary (Box 8, Folder 87)
    - Assorted Programs and Papers Related to Cornell Dramatic Club's 50th Anniversary (Box 8, Folder 88)
    - Booklets from Cornell Dramatic Club's 25th and 50th Anniversary, 1934/1959, 1935/1959 (Box 8, Folder 90)
    - "The Professor and the Critic," Delivered by Sidney Kingsley at the Cornell Dramatic Club's 50th Anniversary, March 7, 1959, March 7, 1959 (Box 8, Folder 94)
  - Performance Photos
    - Photos for Lighting in Goldwin Smith, 1940 (Box 13, Folder 34)
    - Goldwin Smith One-Act Photos, November 1941, November 1941 (Box 13, Folder 35)
    - Production Stills for "Alumni Letter," 1949, 1949 (Box 13, Folder 38)
    - Cornell Dramatic Club at Activities Fair, September 1951, September 1951 (Box 13, Folder 39)
    - "The Brendinennce, Production Prints (Box 13, Folder 40)
    - "Brief Music No Mother," Informal Shots Backstage, Negatives (Box 13, Folder 41)
    - "The Second Man" (Prints) (Box 13, Folder 45)
    - "Comfort Zone" Negative (Box 13, Folder 47)
    - Cornell Dramatic Club Council Meeting/Costume Room Photos (Box 13, Folder 48)
    - "Olympia" (Prints) for Stage Lighting (Box 13, Folder 50)
    - "See Naples and Die" (Prints) (Box 13, Folder 51)
    - "Sound Cabinet" (Negatives) (Box 13, Folder 52)
    - "See Naples and Die" (Negatives) (Box 13, Folder 53)
    - "Island Sign" Photos and Negatives (Box 13, Folder 54)
    - Rehearsal Pictures (Box 13, Folder 57)
    - "The Winslow Boy" Prints, December 1949, December 17, 1949 (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - Miscellaneous
    - Cornell Dramatic Club Documents (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Assorted Newspaper Articles About Cornell Dramatic Club (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Dinner by Dramatic Club for Professor Drummond, May 1952, May 1952 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Unidentified Photo, Possibly Cornell Dramatic Club (Box 8, Folder 60)
    - Activities With the Cooperation of or Under the Auspices of the Cornell Dramatic Club (Box 8, Folder 66)
    - News of Former Cornell Dramatic Club Students (Box 8, Folder 78)
    - Assorted Notes Concerning Cornell Dramatic Club (Box 8, Folder 67)
    - Assorted Cornell Dramatic Club Documents, Includes CDC Ticket from 1914, Playbill from 1968-1969 Season, and Photo of Advertisement for CDC Production of "Romeo and Juliet" (Box 8, Folder 68)
    - Script About Cornell Dramatic Club, July 18, 1938, July 18, 1938 (Box 8, Folder 91)
    - Cornell Dramatic Club Callboard, 1948-1949, 1948-1949 (Box 8, Folder 92)
    - Note Cards from Speech on History of the Cornell Dramatic Club, November 23, 1958, November 23, 1958 (Box 8, Folder 93)
    - Cornell Dramatic Club Roll Book (Box 8, Folder 95)
    - Short Play About Cornell Dramatic Club, "A Dramatic Club Meeting", Play written by Jane Connors, Charlotte Kornit, and Maurice Dell. Also has Stainton as one of the characters. (Box 8, Folder 96)
    - "A Repertory of Plays by the Cornell Dramatic Club," from New York State Fair Commission, 1920, September 13-18, 1920 (Box 8, Folder 108)
    - Lost of Cornell Dramatic Club Presidents, 1920-1947, 1920-1947 (Box 8, Folder 109)
    - Playbills, Advertisements, and Production Details from Cornell Dramatic Club Period Plays, 1950s, 1950s; Includes "Pirates of Penzance," "The Country Wife," and others. (Box 8, Folder 135)
- Series VIII. Other Cornell University Undergraduate Fields and Organizations
  - Cornell WEAI Radio Station
    - Correspondence Concerning Radio Dramas for Cornell, August-December 1930, August-December 1930 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence Concerning Radio Dramas for Cornell, 1931-1932, 1931-1932 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - "The Curtain Rises" by William E. Knepper: Script, June 17, 1930, June 17, 1930 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - "Cinderella" or "What Dreams are Made of": Script (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - "Sire de Haletroit's Door" by Robert Louis Stevenson: Script (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Cornell Radio Station WEAI Papers (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Lists of Titles and Prices of Radio Plays (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Personal Notes on Radio Plays (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - Unlabeled List of Names and Addresses (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - "Serendade" by David Larrimer: Script (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Cornell Productions and Concerts
    - Thomas Wilfred, Clavilux Recital at Bailey Hall, November 6, 1926, November 6, 1926 (Box 4, Folder 49)
    - Articles About Gordon String Quartert at Willard Straight Theatre, 1936, March 1936 (Box 7, Folder 44)
    - MARtha Graham and Dance Group Advertisement, Bailey Hall, April 1941, April 29, 1941 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Cornell R.O.T.C.
    - Assorted R.O.T.C. Papers, 1950-1954, 1950-1954 (Box 7, Folder 58)
    - Transcript of Meeting Between Dean Murdock and Walter H. Stainton on Military Curricula, 1950, October 27, 1950 (Box 7, Folder 59)
    - Cornell Daily Sun Articles About Changes to R.O.T.C. Program, 1952, 1952 (Box 7, Folder 60)
    - R.O.T.C. Related Articles from Cornell Daily Sun, 1953, 1953 (Box 7, Folder 61)
    - "Your Boy and the R.O.T.C.," by President Dodds of Princeton, from "The Atlantic," 1953, March 1953 (Box 7, Folder 62)
    - R.O.T.C. Related Articles from Cornell Daily Sun, 1954, 1954 (Box 7, Folder 63)
    - Minutes and Notes from Committee on Military Curricula, 1954, February 24, 1954 (Box 7, Folder 64)
    - Articles and Changes for R.O.T.C. Students/Programs, May 1954, May 1954 (Box 7, Folder 65)
    - Outline of "The Mission of the Chemical Corps" and Warfare (Box 7, Folder 66)
    - Transcript of Meeting Between Dean Mackesey and Walter H. Stainton on Military Curricula (Box 7, Folder 67)
  - Cornell Summer Theatre
    - Misc. Papers About Cornell Summer Session Theatre, 1946, 1946 (Box 7, Folder 68)
    - Misc. Papers About Cornell Summer Session Theatre, 1947, 1947 (Box 7, Folder 69)
    - Misc. Documents for Summer Theatre, Contains weekly routine for business managers and a playbill from 1948. (Box 7, Folder 70)
    - Misc. Papers About Cornell Summer Session Theatre, 1948, 1948; Includes staff, production details and lists, correspondence, etc. (Box 7, Folder 71)
    - Misc. Papers About Cornell Summer Session Theatre, 1949, 1949; Includes staff, production details and lists, correspondence, etc. (Box 7, Folder 72)
    - Correspondence and Budget/Payroll Information for Summer Theatre, 1949-1952, 1949-1952 (Box 7, Folder 73)
    - Correspondence and Paperwork for Summer Theatre, 1950, 1950 (Box 7, Folder 74)
    - Playbills from Cornell Summer Theatre, July-August 1924, July-August 1924 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Playbills from Cornell Summer Theatre, July-August 1925, July-August 1925 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Cornell Summer Theatre Productions, July-August 1940, July-August 1940 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Playbills from Cornell Summer Theatre, July-August 1940, July-August 1940 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Cornell Summer Theatre Playbills, 1941-1949, 1941-1949 (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Cornell Summer Theatre, July-August 1942, July-August 1942 (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Playbills from Cornell Summer Theatre, July-September 1943, July-September 1943 (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - Playbills from Cornell Summer Theatre, July-August 1944, July-August 1944 (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - Playbills from Cornell Summer Theatre, July-August 1945, July-August 1945 (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - Playbills from Cornell Summer Theatre, July-August 1947, July-August 1947 (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - Playbills from Cornell Summer Theatre, July 1949, July 1949 (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - Documents About Cornell Summer Theatre, 1954, 1954 (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - Playbills for Cornell Summer Theatre, June-August 1952, July-August 1952 (Box 8, Folder 137)
    - Cornell Summer Session Film Program, 1947, 1947 (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Cornell University Theatre, Summer 1951, Summer 1951 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Cornell University Theatre
    - Cornell University Theatre "A Special Anniversary Film Program," 1948, January 11, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Cornell University Theatre Documents (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Technical and Financial Accounts for Theatre and Film, 1925-1950, 1925-1950 (Box 7, Folder 107)
    - Publicity and Related Documents About Museum of Modern Art Films, 1935-1936, 1935-136 (Box 7, Folder 108)
    - Documents for Cornell University Theatre Film Showings (Using Films from Museum of Modern Art Film Library), 1936-1938, 1936-1938 (Box 7, Folder 109)
    - Record of Theatre Attendance, 1939-1951, 1939-1951 (Box 7, Folder 110)
    - Cornell University Theatre Dossier to Theatre Arts for 1940 Issue, 1940 (Box 7, Folder 111)
    - Record of Activities Using the Theatre, 1946-1949, 1946-1949 (Box 7, Folder 112)
    - Letter/Speech and Drama Newsletter Announcing Stainton as Executive Director of University Theatre and Dramatic Club, 1947-1948, 1947-1948 (Box 7, Folder 113)
    - Various Cornell Theatre Records, 1947-1950, 1947-1950 (Box 7, Folder 114)
    - Report on University Finances and Success Through Theatre and Film; Conducted: 1948-1949, Presented: Spring 1950, 1948-1950 (Box 7, Folder 115)
    - Continuation of Financial Report in 7-115, 1946-1949 (Box 7, Folder 116)
    - University Theatre Schedule 2nd Term, 1951-1952, 1951-1952 (Box 7, Folder 117)
    - Cornell Laboratory Theatre Playbills, 1941-1946, 1941-1946 (Box 8, Folder 17)
    - Playbills for the Laboratory Players, 1953, 1953 (Box 8, Folder 18)
    - Information and Regulations for Employees of Cornell University Theatre (Box 8, Folder 32)
    - Cornell University Theatre Account with Tompkins County Trust Company (Box 8, Folder 33)
    - Assorted Photos of Dramatic Performances (Box 8, Folder 34)
    - Advertisements for Cornell University Press, Includes advertisements for "Revolution in the Theatre" by Georg Fuchs and "A Study of Sophoclean Drama" by G.M. Kirkwood. (Box 8, Folder 55)
    - The Cornell Dramatic Club and the Cornell University Theatre, 1940-1942, 1940-1942 (Box 8, Folder 52)
    - Cornell University Theatre, Cornell Dramatic Club, "Manual of Play Production" (Box 8, Folder 97)
    - Cornell University Theatre and Cornell Dramatic Club Prizes in Playwriting, Guidelines and Critique of "Philadelphia Story" (Box 8, Folder 118)
    - "Report on the Latin American Tour Taken by the Cornell University Theatre Summer 1962," September 1962, September 1, 1962 (Box 12, Folder 75)
  - Cornell University Alumni
    - Correspondence With Cornell Alumni, 1948-1949, 1948-1949 (Box 8, Folder 35)
    - Book on Cornell Reunion, 1949, 1949 (Box 8, Folder 36)
    - Articles About Cornell Alumni, 1951-1956, 1951-1956 (Box 8, Folder 37)
    - Alphabetical List of Cornell Alumni (Box 8, Folder 38)
    - Papers Concerning Cornell Dramatic Club Alumni (Box 8, Folder 106)
    - Cornell Alumni News, 1972, December 1972; Focus on Eugene Plumb Andrews, Class of 1896, and his work in the Classics. (Box 9, Folder 47)
    - Cornell Alumni News, February 1973, February 1973 (Box 9, Folder 48)
    - Cornell Alumni News, December 1975, December 1975 (Box 9, Folder 49)
    - Cornell Reunion Booklets, 1950-1951, 1950-1951 (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Cornell Cinema
    - Cornell Cinema Schedules, Late 1970s-Early 1980s, Late 1970s-Early 1980s (Box 9, Folder 32)
    - Cornell Cinema Schedules, Late 1970s-Early 1980s, Late 1970s-Early 1980s (Box 9, Folder 33)
    - Cornell Cinema Schedules, 1980s, 1980s (Box 9, Folder 34)
    - Cornell Cinema Schedules, 1981-1982, 1981-1982 (Box 9, Folder 35)
    - Cornell Cinema Schedules,. 1984-1987, 1984-1987 (Box 9, Folder 36)
  - Cornell Greek Life
    - Alpha Theta Fraternity Papers (Box 9, Folder 50)
    - Correspondence Between Stainton and Alpha Theta Fraternity (Box 9, Folder 51)
    - P. Kappa Alpha: Beta Theta Chapter, Alumni Directory, 1952-1967, 1952-1967 (Box 9, Folder 52)
  - Summer Ithaca
    - Assorted Newspaper Articles About Summer Ithaca and Cornell Festival of Classics, mid-1960s, mid-1960s (Box 12, Folder 33)
    - Assorted Newspaper Articles About Summer Ithaca, mid-1960s, mid-1960s (Box 12, Folder 33)
    - Papers and Correspondence on Summer Ithaca and Ithaca Festival of Classics, 1963-1965, 1963-1965 (Box 12, Folder 38)
    - Summer Ithaca Program, 1963, 1963 (Box 12, Folder 45)
- Series IX. W. H. Stainton Personal and Professional Documents
  - Undergraduate Documents
    - Letters of Correspondence, 1920-1921, 1920-1921 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Newspaper Articles on Edison's Questionnaire, May 1921, May 1921-1922; Also one article on Milton S. Crumb's Marraige, 1922 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Postcards from Newport, New Jersey (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Stainton Cornell Undergraduate Scrapbook, 1916-1921, 1916-1921; Stainton's scrapbook contains various pamphlets, pictures, newspaper articles, and other memorabilia about Cornell between 1916-1921. Among these one may find: a map of the Cornell campus; several examination booklets for subjects such as French, English, German, and Mathematics; programs for productions at the Lyceum Theatre; a form for the Alpha Theta Fraternity; papers and photos concerning involvement with the Military Training Association of the United States and Stainton's time in the United States Army School of Military Aeronautics at Cornell; flyers from several clubs, such as the Cornell University Christian Association, Cornell Rifle Club, and Cornell Dramatic Club; programs and articles concerning the 51st (including here a photo of Hermon Atkins MacNeil and his model of the upcoming Ezra Cornell Statue) and 52nd commencements; and various playbills from Cornell productions. (Box 2)
  - Course Related Documents
    - Student Scores, First Semester 1951-1952, 1951-1952 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Student Information and Scores, Summer Session 1953, 1953; Classes taken include Dramatic Production Direction and The Motion Picture. (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Student Information and Scores, First Term 1953-1954, 1953-1954 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Student Course Scores, 1954-1956, 1954-1956 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Assessments for Speech and Drama Courses (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Reading Lists for Speech and Drama Courses (Box 5, Folder 38)
    - Typed Material for Speech and Drama Courses (Box 5, Folder 39)
    - Grade Books from 1922-1927, 1922-1927 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Examinations for Speech and Drama 431, 1928-1950, 1928-1950 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Speech and Drama Prelim, 1947, March 18, 1947 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Special Examination on Dolman's "The Fine Art of Play Production," 1948, October 18, 1948 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Special Examination on Dolman's "The Art of Play Production," 1949, October 18, 1949 (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Documents for Speech and Drama 482, 1956-1962, 1956-1962 (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Exams for Speech and Drama 375, 480, 481; 1957-1965, 1957-1965 (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Proposals for New Film Course, 1958, January 28, 1958 (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Schedules for Speech and Drama 482 and 376, 1958-1963, 1958-1963 (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Examinations for Speech and Drama 376, 482; 1959-1965, 1959-1965 (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - Examinations for Speech and Drama 431 (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - Documents for Public Speaking 33, 1927, Summer 1927 (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - Notes on Russian Films for Class 375, 1962-1963, 1962-1963 (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - "List of One Act Plays Submitted By Members of the Class," 1947, October 15, 1947 (Box 10, Folder 52)
    - "List of One Act Plays Submitted By Members of the Class," 1948, January 21, 1948 (Box 10, Folder 53)
    - "List of One Act Plays Submitted By Members of the Class," 1948, December 1, 1948 (Box 10, Folder 54)
    - Speech and Drama 437: Stage Lighting (Box 11, Folder 50)
    - Examination for Speech and Drama 437 (Box 11, Folder 51)
    - Documents and Notes for Speech and Drama Lighting Course (Box 11, Folder 52)
    - Speech and Drama 385, Advanced Direction (Box 11, Folder 53)
    - Speech and Drama 480, Examinations, Late 1950s, Late 1950s (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Speech and Drama 480, Examinations, Late 1950s, Late 1950s (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - "Walking Exercise" for Floor Plans, April 1960, April 1960 (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Bibliography and Reading List for Theatre Production (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Notes, Articles, and Resources for Speech and Drama courses (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Reading Lists for Speech and Drama Classes (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Quotes and Extracts for Speech and Drama 401 (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - "Walking Exercise" For Stainton's Courses (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Speech and Drama 401, Final Examination (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - Papers on Play Production (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - Notes and Papers for Speech and Drama 401 (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - Speech and Drama 401 Calendar, 1949 (Box 12, Folder 12)
    - Papers from Speech and Drama 90 and 91: Theatre Practice (Box 12, Folder 30)
    - Various Information About Theatre Courses (Box 12, Folder 79)
    - Assorted Information About College Film Courses (Box 12, Folder 80)
    - Assorted Information About College Theatre Courses (Box 12, Folder 81)
    - Summer Session Film Program, 1949 (Box 13, Folder 62)
    - Summer Session Film Program, 1949-1952 (Box 13, Folder 63)
    - Film Information for Speech and Drama 376 (Box 13, Folder 67)
    - Syllabus for Speech and Drama 376: "Documentary and Experimental": Spring 1967, Spring 1967 (Box 15, Folder 23)
  - Student Papers and Research
    - "The Theatre-Real or Unreal: Bakshy's Theory of Presentation," by Ulric Moore, 1933, September 15, 1933 (Box 12, Folder 13)
    - "Bertolt Brecht" by Jonnie Gravel, 1953, May 26, 1953; This paper was written for Stainton's course Speech and Drama 485 (Box 12, Folder 14)
    - "A Comparison of the Theories of Appia and Copeau," Dorothy Skriletz, 1956, March 13, 1956 (Box 12, Folder 15)
    - "Jacques Copeau: Man of the Theatre (1879-1949)" by H.H. Hewitt, 1958, May 25, 1958 (Box 12, Folder 16)
    - "Living Art or Dead Nature?" by Adolphe Appia, Spring 1960, Spring 1960 (Box 12, Folder 17)
    - "Jacques Copeau, Reformer," by Dale Burg, 1963, May 29, 1963 (Box 12, Folder 18)
    - "Naturalism and the Theater," by Otto Brahm, Trans. By Walter B. Ross, 1964 (Box 12, Folder 19)
    - Papers on Appia by Alton W. Powell, 1965, 1965 (Box 12, Folder 20)